88 Canterbury Rd., Brewer, ME 04412

Jonathan Cole

Cell: (207) 949-4265 | Email: joncole04412@gmail.com

joncole.me | github.com/seieibob | linkedin.com/in/joncole04412

Professional Summary

I am a graduate student and software developer at the University of Maine. Through my work I have gained a broad skill set, and have worked on projects ranging from research-oriented virtual reality (VR) simulations to augmented reality (AR) hardware projects to frontend web interfaces for open video annotation models. I seek to continue my work in bringing innovation to human-centric computing that matters.

Skills

- Languages include C#, Python, Swift, C++, and Java
- Unity3D and interactive design in VR (HTC Vive, Oculus Rift, Leap Motion)
- OpenCV and computer vision techniques
- Mobile app development
- Human-Computer Interaction
- Agile/Scrum

Experience

Software Developer

Virtual Environment and Multimodal Interaction Lab (vemilab.org) – University of Maine, Orono, ME September 2011 – Present

- Created several projects across multiple domains, including virtual and augmented reality
- Developed several VR/AR simulations using Unity3D; responsible for code, art, and level design in both solo and team projects
- Created an immersive VR driving simulator which evaluates driving behaviors in an experimental setting; used to study the effects of age-related eye disease on driving ability
- Worked with several human interface devices, including the Leap Motion, HTC Vive, Microsoft Kinect, and optical marker tracking systems by Phasespace and WorldViz
- Currently working with Dartmouth faculty on a web-facing implementation of an open video annotation model
- Designed architectural visualizers for iOS and Android

Graduate Teaching Assistant

Computer Science Department – University of Maine, Orono, ME

September 2015 – Present

- Courses include Introductory Visual Basic, Introductory C++, Introductory Python, and Data Structures
 in C++
- Graded and consulted for ~80 students per semester

Customer Specialist

Best Buy - Bangor, ME

August 2009 – September 2011

- Responsible for customer interaction and computer sales in an interactive team environment
- Learned about the climate of the consumer electronics market

Education

B.S. – Computer Science University of Maine, Orono

Spring 2015

• Final research project was the creation of an augmented reality hardware extension for the Oculus Rift. Significant focus was given to high-performance computer vision.

M.S. – Spatial Information Science and Engineering University of Maine, Orono

Spring 2017 (Expected)

- Skills/domains learned include ArcGIS, R, Prolog, spatial statistics, databases, and data streams
- Research focus on augmented reality for sensory compensation

Additional Information

- Three-time winner of the University of Maine Center for Undergraduate Research (CUGR) grant award
- Mensa member
- Created personal projects in Unity3D, from games to inspector extensions for EMGU
- Developed iOS app for an exhibit in the Children's Discovery Museum in Bangor, Maine
- Second-degree black belt in Taekwondo
- Played trumpet and French horn for symphonic, concert, and pep bands